Hello and welcome back. We're almost at the end of our Week 3 and
大家好 欢迎回来 第3周的学习已经接近尾声
I want to conclude the technical content of this week with some brief comments
下面我想简单概括一下这周技术性的内容
about gradients and about edges and about gradients in high dimensions basically
主要有关梯度和边缘 以及彩色图像的高维梯度化
for color images. So, the topic of this relatively short
那么这个相对较短的视频要讲的是梯度化
video is gradients. And we see here, age detection and
请看这行字 边缘检测 (edge detection) 和彩色边检测 (color edge detection)
coloration detection because that's what they are related to for image processing.
因为这正是它们与图像处理有关的地方
So, the basic idea is very simple and you have learn about gradients probably in
基本思想非常简单 而大家 可能就在最近 也可能是很久以前
your Calculus classes, maybe recently, maybe a long time ago.
应该就已经在微积分课堂上学过梯度的相关概念
And what I want to talk with you is about gradients.
而今天我想向大家介绍的内容就是有关梯度
The gradient of an image F is actually a vector.
图像F的梯度事实上是一个矢量
An image is a scalar. At every point we have a value.
图像本身是一个标量 每一点对应一个值
The gradient is actually a vector. It's the derivative of F in the x
而梯度则是一个矢量 这是F在矢量坐标轴x方向的导数
direction, that's one coordinate of the vector and the derivative of F in the y
它是第一个坐标 以及这是F在y方向上的导数
direction. That's the other coordinate of the
y方向的导数 这就是矢量的第二个坐标
vector. We have already seen that derivatives are
我们都知道导数是非常重要的
very important. They actually led us to detect edges.
它们能帮助我们检测边缘
They led us to detect big changes in images.
引导我们检测图像中的明显变化
We have seen that and we remember that as well from our early classes in Calculus.
我们在之前的微积分课中学过并记住了这些
If we have a step, basically, a sharp change that the derivative of that is the
假如有这么一级台阶 就是像这样的突变 它的导数是一个脉冲函数(delta function)
delta function, so it helps you to detect those edges and with unsharp masking
那可以利用它来检测边缘
[UNKNOWN] techniques will help us to enhance images that may be a blur or may
而利用反锐化掩模或者其他技术 可以帮助我们来增强一些图像
be which we just want to enhance their edges so we can observe them better.
或者是因为它们模糊不清 或者是为了能更好地观察图像
Now, the gradient is one important derivative and one of the important
可见 梯度是一个重要的导数 有着重要的特性
characteristics, in case you don't remember that from your earlier class,
为了防止你忘记之前课程的内容
classes, is that when you see at the certain pixel
当你看到图像中像这里的一个像素
in the image and you ask yourself, in which direction is my image changing the
你可能会问 这幅图像在哪个方向变化得最快呢？
most?" So, in which direction should I make a walk, a step, and I get a big jump
而我应该在哪个方向进行变化 从而大幅改变图像的像素值呢？
in the pixel values of my image? It turns out that that direction is the
最后你会发现那个方向正是梯度方向
gradient. So, when you're saying, for example, this
这是一种用途
is an object., And you say, which way should I go" to
另外 在哪个方向
have the maximal change in my pixel value?
有着像素值的最大变化呢？
That is the gradient direction. This gives you the direction of the
答案是梯度方向 梯度给出了图像的最大变化方向
maximal change in your image. So, it's a very, very interesting object.
这是一个非常非常有趣的地方
How much are you changing? That's what's called the absolute value
那么改变了多少呢？
of the gradient. So, the absolute value of the gradient of
这就是梯度的绝对值
F, that's basically the definition of the absolute value or the magnitude of a
F的梯度绝对值 就定义为矢量的绝对值大小
vector. Just a square root of the square of the
就等于 x方向导数的平方与
derivative in the x direction and the square of the derivative in the y
y方向导数的平方的和 开根号
direction. That's how much you're actually jumping,
这就是真正变化的跨度
how much you are changing the gray value when you advance in the gradient
也正是灰度值在梯度方向前进时的改变量
direction. In any other direction, you're going to
在任何其他的方向
be changing equal or less than that value.
变化量都小于等于这个值
In particular, there is one direction that you're not going to be changing at
另外 还有一个方向完全没有变化
all, and that's the direction perpendicular to the gradient.
这就是梯度的法线方向
If your moving the gradient direction, you have the highest jump.
如果沿着梯度方向 就有着最大的变化量
If you move perpendicular to it, you have the lowest jump, actually zero.
而沿着梯度法线方向则有着最小的变化量 也就是0
That's called the lever's edge and we're going to talk much more about that in a
这就是水平集 (lever sets) 我们将在几周后进行介绍
few weeks. So, this is the concept of gradient.
这些就是梯度的概念
You compute the derivatives, you compute the magnitude, and you're going to get
通过计算出导数方向及其大小
basically, the amount of jump when you go from one pixel to just the neighbor
就可以得到一个像素到相邻像素的数值变化量
pixels. Now, this whole concept also exists for
以上这些概念对矢量图像同样适用
vector images. So, instead of having just one image, I
那么如果不是标量图像
have an RGB image, a polar image. Now, at every point, I have three values
而是RGB图像 也就是极坐标图像 也就是在每一点有三个值的话
and I can ask the same question, in which direction do I have the maximal change of
同样地 在哪个方向这三个值能够同时有最大变化量呢？
these three values at the same time? You could actually ask for each value
其实可以对每一个值单独求解
independently. You could say, in which direction does
也就是 在什么方向红色变化量最大
the red changed the most, in which direction the green, in which direction
绿色在什么方向变化量最大
the blue, and that's very simple, very simply three gradient directions.
以及蓝色 这是三个非常简单的梯度方向
You're going to get three different directions sometimes, or you could say, I
有时会得到三个不同的方向
want them to change at the same time. In which one of the directions I have the
或者 需要让它们同时变化
biggest change as a vector? At the same time, red, green, and blue,
在哪一个矢量方向上 红绿蓝同时有着最大的变化量呢？
when I basically accumulate the change is the maximal possible change.
此时累积变化量就是可能得到的最大变化量
And that concept also exist is the concept of the gradient of factorial
这个概念对于阶乘图像的梯度也是一样
images is not very hard to compute, but we're going to skip that for now, but
而且并不难计算 不过我们先不讨论
you're also going to get that direction and there's going to be a close formula,
你只需通过一个与此类似的公式 就可以得到一个方向
like we have here, that tells you in which direction you have the maximal
这个等式告诉你 你可以在哪个方向上
change in the vector, in the whole colors.
得到所有颜色的矢量的最大变化量
You're going to have, once again, a direction, and once again, a maximal
计算结果会是一个方向 以及一个最大值
value. That basically is an extension of the
这就是梯度概念
concept of gradient for vector images like RGB images.
在RGB图像这类矢量图像上的扩展
So, I wanted you to know about that concept.
我希望大家能够掌握这一概念
I wanted you to know about the concept of gradients and the concept of vector
掌握关于梯度和矢量的概念
gradients. And what we are going to do, is in the
而在下面的视频中
next video, we're going to conclude this very, very useful week that we had.
我将概括一下本周所学的这些非常实用的内容
Thank you.
谢谢大家